I'm a lifelong traveler.
سافرت طوال حياتي.
Even as a little kid,
حتى عندما كنت طفلا،
I was actually working out that it would be cheaper
كنت أفكر أن الأمر سيكلف أقل
to go to boarding school in England
إن ذهبت إلى مدرسة داخلية في بريطانيا
than just to the best school down the road from my parents' house in California.
من أن أذهب إلى أفضل مدرسة قريبة من منزل والدي في كاليفورنيا.
So, from the time I was nine years old
لذلك، منذ أن بلغت 9 سنوات
I was flying alone several times a year
كنت أسافر بمفردي بالطائرة عدة مرات في السنة
over the North Pole, just to go to school.
فوق القطب الشمالي، لكي أذهب إلى المدرسة.
And of course the more I flew the more I came to love to fly,
وبالتأكيد، كلما سافرت بالطائرة، كلما أحببت الطيران أكثر،
so the very week after I graduated from high school,
لذا بحلول الأسبوع الموالي لتخرجي من الثانوية،
I got a job mopping tables
حصلت على عمل كمنظف للطاولات
so that I could spend every season of my 18th year
لكي أستطيع أن أقضي كل فصل من سنتي الثامنة عشرة
on a different continent.
في قارة مختلفة.
And then, almost inevitably, I became a travel writer
وبعدها بكل تأكيد أصبحت كاتب أسفار
so my job and my joy could become one.
وبذلك جمعت بين عملي ومتعتي معا.
And I really began to feel that if you were lucky enough
وفعلا بدأت أحس أنك إن كنت محظوظا بما يكفي
to walk around the candlelit temples of Tibet
بأن تتجول حول معابد التيبت المضاءة بالشموع،
or to wander along the seafronts in Havana
أو تتأمل في الواجهات المائية في هافانا
with music passing all around you,
مع موسيقى تحيط بك من كل مكان،
you could bring those sounds and the high cobalt skies
فإنه بإمكانك أن تجلب تلك الأصوات وتلك السماوات الفضية العالية
and the flash of the blue ocean
وبريق المحيط الأزرق
back to your friends at home,
إلى أصدقائك حين تعود للديار،
and really bring some magic
ويمكنك فعلا أن تدخل بعض السحر
and clarity to your own life.
والوضوح إلى حياتك.
Except, as you all know,
إلا أنه، كما تعلمون جميعا،
one of the first things you learn when you travel
أن أولى الأشياء التي تتعلمها حين تسافر
is that nowhere is magical unless you can bring the right eyes to it.
أنه لا مكان يبدو سحريا إلا إذا رأيته رؤية صحيحة.
You take an angry man to the Himalayas,
إذا أخذت رجلا عبوسا إلى الهيمالايا،
he just starts complaining about the food.
فإنه سيتذمر من الطعام فحسب.
And I found that the best way
ولقد توصلت إلى أن أفضل طريقة
that I could develop more attentive and more appreciative eyes
يمكن بها أن أطور رؤية أكثر يقظة وتقديرا
was, oddly,
كانت، بكل غرابة،
by going nowhere, just by sitting still.
هي ألا أذهب إلى أي مكان، وأن أظل ساكنا.
And of course sitting still is how many of us get
وبالتأكيد، السكون هو ما يتوق إليه
what we most crave and need in our accelerated lives, a break.
معظمنا وما نحتاجه في حياتنا المتسارعة، ألا وهو العطلة.
But it was also the only way
لكنها كانت الطريقة الوحيدة
that I could find to sift through the slideshow of my experience
التي وجدتها كي أستطيع التدقيق من خلال شريط أحداث تجربتي
and make sense of the future and the past.
وإيجاد معنى لمستقبلي وماضي.
And so, to my great surprise,
وبالتالي، وهنا كانت المفاجئة الكبرى،
I found that going nowhere
وجدت أن عدم الذهاب لأي مكان
was at least as exciting as going to Tibet or to Cuba.
كان بقدر الحماسة لو ذهبت إلى التيبت أو كوبا.
And by going nowhere, I mean nothing more intimidating
وما أعنيه بعدم الذهاب لأي مكان، أقصد ما من شيء محرج
than taking a few minutes out of every day
أكثر من أخذ بضع دقائق من كل يوم
or a few days out of every season,
أو بضعة أيام من كل فصل،
or even, as some people do,
أو حتى، كما يفعل البعض،
a few years out of a life
أخذ بضع سنوات من العمر
in order to sit still long enough
لكي تلتزم السكون بما يكفي
to find out what moves you most,
لكي تجد ما الذي يحركك أكثر،
to recall where your truest happiness lies
ولتتذكر أين تكمن سعادتك الحقيقية
and to remember that sometimes
ولتتذكر أنه أحيانا
making a living and making a life
العيش والحياة
point in opposite directions.
يتجهان في اتجاهين متعاكسين.
And of course, this is what wise beings through the centuries
وبالتأكيد، هذا ما كان يخبرنا به
from every tradition have been telling us.
الحكماء من كل الثقافات خلال القرون الماضية.
It's an old idea.
إنها فكرة قديمة.
More than 2,000 years ago, the Stoics were reminding us
منذ 2000 سنة ذكرنا الرواقيون
it's not our experience that makes our lives,
أنه ليست التجربة هي من تصنع حياتنا،
it's what we do with it.
بل ما نفعله بها.
Imagine a hurricane suddenly sweeps through your town
تخيل أن إعصارا ضرب فجأة بلدتك
and reduces every last thing to rubble.
وحول كل شيء إلى ركام.
One man is traumatized for life.
سيكون هناك من سيبقى مصدوما طوال حياته.
But another, maybe even his brother, almost feels liberated,
لكن شخصا آخر، ربما يكون أخاه، قد يشعر أنه تحرر،
and decides this is a great chance to start his life anew.
ويقرر أن هذه فرصة عظيمة ليبدأ الحياة من جديد.
It's exactly the same event,
إنه الحدث نفسه تماما.
but radically different responses.
لكن بردات فعل مختلفة تماما.
There is nothing either good or bad, as Shakespeare told us in "Hamlet,"
ليس هناك أمر جيد وآخر سيء، كما قال شيكسبير في "هامليت"،
but thinking makes it so.
لكن التفكير هو ما يجعله كذلك.
And this has certainly been my experience as a traveler.
هذا بالتأكيد ما كانت عليه تجربتي كرحالة.
Twenty-four years ago I took the most mind-bending trip
منذ 24 سنة ذهبت في أكثر رحلاتي إثارة للدهشة
across North Korea.
عبر كوريا الشمالية.
But the trip lasted a few days.
دامت رحلتي بضعة أيام.
What I've done with it sitting still, going back to it in my head,
ما قمت به حينها ملتزما السكون أنني عدت إلى هناك بذاكرتي،
trying to understand it, finding a place for it in my thinking,
محاولا أن أفهمها، وأن أجد مكانا لها في تفكيري،
that's lasted 24 years already
الذي دام 24 سنة
and will probably last a lifetime.
والذي ربما قد يدوم طوال حياتي.
The trip, in other words, gave me some amazing sights,
السفر، بعبارة أخرى، يعطيني مناظر رائعة،
but it's only sitting still
لكن السكون
that allows me to turn those into lasting insights.
هو ما يجعلني أحولها إلى رؤى خالدة.
And I sometimes think that so much of our life
وفي بعض الأحيان، أفكر أن الكثير من حياتنا
takes place inside our heads,
تحدث داخل عقولنا،
in memory or imagination or interpretation or speculation,
في الذاكرة، أو الخيال أو التأويل أو التخمين،
that if I really want to change my life
وأنه إن كنت أريد فعلا أن أغير حياتي
I might best begin by changing my mind.
فمن الأفضل أن أبدأ بتغيير تفكيري.
Again, none of this is new;
مجددا، لم يكن هذا أمرا جديدا،
that's why Shakespeare and the Stoics were telling us this centuries ago,
لذلك فقد أخبرنا شكسبير والرواقيون بهذا منذ قرون خلت،
but Shakespeare never had to face 200 emails in a day.
لكن لم يكن شكسبير مجبرا على الرد على200 رسالة إلكترونية يوميا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The Stoics, as far as I know, were not on Facebook.
لم يكن الرواقيون، على حد علمي، على الفايسبوك.
We all know that in our on-demand lives,
نعلم جميعا أننا في حياتنا ذات المتطلبات الكثيرة،
one of the things that's most on demand
أن المتطلب الأكبر
is ourselves.
هو أنفسنا.
Wherever we are, any time of night or day,
أينما كنا، صباح مساء،
our bosses, junk-mailers, our parents can get to us.
يمكن لرؤسائنا، آبائنا ومرسلي البريد غير المرغوب فيه أن يصلوا إلينا.
Sociologists have actually found that in recent years
وجد العلماء الاجتماعيون أن الأمريكيين في السنوات الأخيرة
Americans are working fewer hours than 50 years ago,
يعملون ساعات أقل عما كان عليه الأمر منذ 50 سنة،
but we feel as if we're working more.
لكننا نشعر وكأننا نعمل أكثر.
We have more and more time-saving devices,
لدينا المزيد من الأجهزة التي توفر الوقت،
but sometimes, it seems, less and less time.
لكن في بعض الأحيان، يبدو أن الوقت يقل أكثر.
We can more and more easily make contact with people
يمكننا القيام بالمزيد من التواصل مع الناس
on the furthest corners of the planet,
في الأصقاع البعيدة من العالم،
but sometimes in that process
لكن في أحيان كثيرة ونحن في هذا الخضم،
we lose contact with ourselves.
نفقد التواصل مع أنفسنا.
And one of my biggest surprises as a traveler
إحدى المفاجآت الكبرى التي اكتشفتها كرحالة
has been to find that often it's exactly the people
أنه في معظم الأحيان، أولئك الناس
who have most enabled us to get anywhere
الذين يمكنوننا من الوصول إلى أي مكان
who are intent on going nowhere.
هم من يصرون على البقاء في أماكنهم.
In other words, precisely those beings
بمعنى آخر، هؤلاء الأشخاص أنفسهم
who have created the technologies
الذين خلقوا التكنولوجيا
that override so many of the limits of old,
التي محت العديد من المعوقات القديمة،
are the ones wisest about the need for limits,
هم أولئك الذين هم أكثر وعيا بضرورة وجود حدود،
even when it comes to technology.
حتى حينما يتعلق الأمر بالتكنولوجيا.
I once went to the Google headquarters
ذهبت مرة إلى المقر الرئيسي لغوغل
and I saw all the things many of you have heard about;
ورأيت كل تلك الأشياء التي سمعتم عنها،
the indoor tree houses, the trampolines,
منازل الأشجار في الداخل والمنصات البهلوانية،
workers at that time enjoying 20 percent of their paid time free
الموظفون الذين كانوا حينها يستمتعون ب20 في المئة من وقت عملهم بالمجان
so that they could just let their imaginations go wandering.
لكي يطلقوا العنان لخيالهم.
But what impressed me even more
لكن ما أدهشني بشكل أكبر
was that as I was waiting for my digital I.D.,
أنني حين كنت أنتظر بطاقتي الرقمية
one Googler was telling me about the program
كان أحد موظفي غوغل قد أخبرني عن برنامج
that he was about to start to teach the many, many Googlers
كان بصدد بداية تعليمه للعديد من موظفي غوغل
who practice yoga to become trainers in it,
الذين كانوا يما رسون اليوغا ليصبحوا مدربين لها،
and the other Googler was telling me about the book that he was about to write
وموظف آخر أخبرني عن الكتاب الذي كان بصدد كتابته
on the inner search engine,
حول محرك البحث الداخلي،
and the ways in which science has empirically shown
وكيف أن العلم أثبت
that sitting still, or meditation,
أن السكون، أو التأمل
can lead not just to better health or to clearer thinking,
يمكن أن يوصلك ليس فقط لصحة أفضل، أو لتفكير أوضح،
but even to emotional intelligence.
بل للذكاء العاطفي.
I have another friend in Silicon Valley
لي صديق آخر يعمل بالسيليكون فالي،
who is really one of the most eloquent spokesmen
وكان من أفصح المتحدثين
for the latest technologies,
عن التكنلوجيا الحديثة،
and in fact was one of the founders of Wired magazine, Kevin Kelly.
وفي الواقع، فقد كان أحد مؤسسي مجلة وايرد ماغازين، إنه كيفين كيلي.
And Kevin wrote his last book on fresh technologies
وقد كتب كيفن كتابه الأخير عن التكنولوجيا الحديثة
without a smartphone or a laptop or a TV in his home.
دون أن يكون لديه هاتف ذكي، أو حاسوب أو تلفاز في البيت.
And like many in Silicon Valley,
وكما هو الحال بالنسبة للكثيرين في السيليكون فالي،
he tries really hard to observe
فقد حاول جادا أن يقوم
what they call an Internet sabbath,
بما يسمونه سبت الانقطاع عن الانترنت،
whereby for 24 or 48 hours every week
حيث يغيبون تماما كل أسبوع عن الانترنت
they go completely offline
لمدة 24 أو 48 ساعة
in order to gather the sense of direction
لكي يستجمعوا قواهم التوجيهية والتناسبية
and proportion they'll need when they go online again.
والتي سيحتاجونها حين يعودون إلى الانترنت مجددا.
The one thing perhaps that technology hasn't always given us
الشيء الوحيد الذي لم تمنحه إيانا التكنولوجيا ربما
is a sense of how to make the wisest use of technology.
هو بشكل ما كيفية استعمالها بشكل رشيد.
And when you speak of the sabbath,
وحين نتكلم عن السبت،
look at the Ten Commandments --
انظر إلى الوصايا العشر--
there's only one word there for which the adjective "holy" is used,
كانت هناك كلمة واحدة حيث استعملت كلمة "مقدس" لوصفها
and that's the Sabbath.
ألا وهي السبت.
I pick up the Jewish holy book of the Torah --
حين أنظر إلى الكتاب المقدس لليهود وهو التوراة
its longest chapter, it's on the Sabbath.
فصله المطول، كان عن السبت.
And we all know that it's really one of our greatest luxuries,
وكلنا يعلم أنه من مظاهر الفخامة
the empty space.
الفضاء الفارغ.
In many a piece of music, it's the pause or the rest
في العديد من المقطوعات الموسيقية، إنها الوقفات أو الاستراحات
that gives the piece its beauty and its shape.
التي تعطي المقطوعة جماليتها وشكلها.
And I know I as a writer
وأعلم بما أنني كاتب
will often try to include a lot of empty space on the page
أنني غالبا ما أدخل الكثير من الفراغات في صفحاتي
so that the reader can complete my thoughts and sentences
لكي يكمل القارئ أفكاري وجملي
and so that her imagination has room to breathe.
ولكي أعطي لخيالهم مجالا ليتنفس.
Now, in the physical domain, of course, many people,
الآن،في المجال المادي،بالتأكيد، فسيحاول العديد من الناس
if they have the resources,
إن كانت لديهم الإمكانيات
will try to get a place in the country, a second home.
أن يحصلوا على بيت في البادية، كمسكن ثانوي.
I've never begun to have those resources,
لم أبدأ قط في تحصيل هذه الإمكانيات،
but I sometimes remember that any time I want,
لكنني أتذكر أنه في كل مرة أرغب في ذلك،
I can get a second home in time, if not in space,
فإنني أحصل على مسكن ثانوي عبر الزمن، إن لم يكن في المكان،
just by taking a day off.
عن طريق أخذ عطلة من يوم واحد.
And it's never easy because, of course, whenever I do I spend much of it
وليس الأمر بالهين بتاتا، بالتأكيد، لأنني كلما فعلت فأنني أقضي معظم الوقت
worried about all the extra stuff
قلقا من كمية العمل الإضافية
that's going to crash down on me the following day.
التي ستسقط على رأسي في اليوم الموالي.
I sometimes think I'd rather give up meat or sex or wine
أفكر أحيانا أنه من الأفضل أن أتخلى عن اللحم أو الجنس أو الخمر
than the chance to check on my emails.
على فرصة قراءة بريدي الإلكتروني.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And every season I do try to take three days off on retreat
وفي كل فصل أحاول الحصول على 3 أيام كعطلة
but a part of me still feels guilty to be leaving my poor wife behind
لكن جزء مني يحس بالذنب لأنني سأترك زوجتي المسكينة وحيدة
and to be ignoring all those seemingly urgent emails
وسأتجاهل تلك الرسائل الإلكترونية التي تبدو وكأنها مهمة
from my bosses
من طرف رؤسائي
and maybe to be missing a friend's birthday party.
وربما سأفوت حفلة عيد ميلاد أحد أصدقائي.
But as soon as I get to a place of real quiet,
لكنني سرعان ما أصل إلى مكان يغمره الهدوء،
I realize that it's only by going there
أدرك أنه فقط بالتوجه إلى هناك
that I'll have anything fresh or creative or joyful to share
ستكون لي أشياء جديدة ومبدعة ومبهجة لأتقاسمها
with my wife or bosses or friends.
مع زوجتي أو رؤسائي أو أصدقائي.
Otherwise, really,
عكس ذلك،
I'm just foisting on them my exhaustion or my distractedness,
فإنني فقط أدس لهم تعبي وتشوش أفكاري،
which is no blessing at all.
والذي لا يعتبر أمرا رائعا البتة.
And so when I was 29,
لذا فعندما كنت في 29 من عمري،
I decided to remake my entire life
قررت أن أعيد صياغة حياتي كلها
in the light of going nowhere.
على ضوء فكرة البقاء في مكاني.
One evening I was coming back from the office,
ذات مساء، كنت عائدا من مكتبي
it was after midnight, I was in a taxi driving through Times Square,
بعد منتصف الليل، كنت داخل سيارة أجرة في طريقها عبر تايمز سكوير؛
and I suddenly realized that I was racing around so much
وفجأة أدركت أنني كنت أركض في كل اتجاه بكثرة
I could never catch up with my life.
دون أن أستطيع اللحاق بحياتي.
And my life then, as it happened,
وقد كانت حياتي حينها،على ما يبدو،
was pretty much the one I might have dreamed of as a little boy.
هي تلك التي كنت أحلم بها عندما كنت طفلا صغيرا.
I had really interesting friends and colleagues,
كان لدي أصدقاء وزملاء مثيرون للاهتمام،
I had a nice apartment on Park Avenue and 20th Street.
كانت لدي شقة جميلة في تقاطع جادة بارك والشارع 20.
I had, to me, a fascinating job writing about world affairs,
كان لدي، بالنسبة لي، عمل رائع في الكتابة حول الشؤون الدولية،
but I could never separate myself enough from them
لكنني لم أكن أستطيع أبدا الانفصال عنها بما يكفي
to hear myself think --
لكي أنصت لنفسي
or really, to understand if I was truly happy.
أو بالفعل، لأفهم إن كنت فعلا سعيدا.
And so, I abandoned my dream life
وبالتالي،هجرت حياة أحلامي
for a single room on the backstreets of Kyoto, Japan,
إلى غرفة فردية في الشوارع الخلفية في كيوطو في اليابان،
which was the place that had long exerted a strong,
التي كانت المدينة التي مارست
really mysterious gravitational pull on me.
قوة جاذبية سحرية كبيرة علي.
Even as a child
حتى عندما كنت طفلا
I would just look at a painting of Kyoto and feel I recognized it;
كنت أنظر إلى لوحة كيوطو فقط لأتعرف عليها؛
I knew it before I ever laid eyes on it.
كنت أعرفها قبل أن تقع عيني عليها.
But it's also, as you all know,
لكنها أيضا، كما تعلمون،
a beautiful city encircled by hills,
مدينة جميلة محاطة بالتلال،
filled with more than 2,000 temples and shrines,
مليئة بأكثر من 2000 معبد وضريح،
where people have been sitting still for 800 years or more.
حيث التزم الناس السكون طوال 800 سنة أو يزيد.
And quite soon after I moved there, I ended up where I still am
وبعد فترة قصيرة من انتقالي هناك، انتهى بي المطاف حيث أنا الآن
with my wife, formerly our kids,
مع زوجتي وأطفالي السابقين،
in a two-room apartment in the middle of nowhere
في شقة ذات طابقين في مكان منعزل
where we have no bicycle, no car,
حيث لا نتوفر على سيارة أو دراجة
no TV I can understand,
أو تلفاز أفهمه،
and I still have to support my loved ones
ولا أزال بحاجة لدعم أحبائي
as a travel writer and a journalist,
ككاتب رحلات وكصحفي،
so clearly this is not ideal for job advancement
وبكل وضوح فإن هذا ليس مثاليا من أجل إحراز تقدم في العمل
or for cultural excitement
أو إشعاع ثقافي
or for social diversion.
أو تنوع اجتماعي.
But I realized that it gives me what I prize most,
لكنني أدركت أن هذا يمنحني ما أصبو إليه أكثر
which is days
وهي الأيام،
and hours.
والساعات.
I have never once had to use a cell phone there.
لم أكن قط بحاجة لاستعمال الهاتف النقال هناك.
I almost never have to look at the time,
ولم أكن بحاجة تقريبا للنظر إلى الوقت؛
and every morning when I wake up,
وحين أستيقظ كل صباح،
really the day stretches in front of me
فإن اليوم يتمدد أمامي فعلا
like an open meadow.
كالمرج الفسيح.
And when life throws up one of its nasty surprises,
وحين ترميني الحياة بإحدى مفاجآتها البغيضة،
as it will, more than once,
كما ستفعل، أكثر من مرة،
when a doctor comes into my room
حين يدخل الطبيب إلى غرفتي
wearing a grave expression,
وعليه علامات الأسى،
or a car suddenly veers in front of mine on the freeway,
أو حين تنحرف سيارة أمامي فجأة في الطريق السيار،
I know, in my bones,
أدرك، بكل ما في،
that it's the time I've spent going nowhere
أن الوقت الذي قضيته دون أن أذهب إلى أي مكان
that is going to sustain me much more
هو الذي سيظل أكثر بكثير
than all the time I've spent racing around to Bhutan or Easter Island.
من كل ذلك الوقت الذي قضيته متجولا حول بوتان أو جزيرة إيستر.
I'll always be a traveler --
سأظل دائما رحالة،
my livelihood depends on it --
معيشتي متوقفة على هذا--
but one of the beauties of travel
لكن إحدى جماليات السفر
is that it allows you to bring stillness
أنه يمكنك من إدخال السكون
into the motion and the commotion of the world.
إلى حركة واهتزاز العالم.
I once got on a plane in Frankfurt, Germany,
ركبت الطائرة مرة في فرانكفورت، ألمانيا،
and a young German woman came down and sat next to me
فجاءت شابة ألمانية وجلست إلى جانبي
and engaged me in a very friendly conversation
وأدخلتني في حديث ودي جدا
for about 30 minutes,
لمدة 30 دقيقة تقريبا،
and then she just turned around
بعدها استدارت،
and sat still for 12 hours.
والتزمت السكون لمدة 12 ساعة.
She didn't once turn on her video monitor,
لم تلتفت قط إلى جهاز الفيديو أمامها،
she never pulled out a book, she didn't even go to sleep,
لم تخرج كتابا، حتى أنها لم تنم،
she just sat still,
التزمت السكون؛
and something of her clarity and calm really imparted itself to me.
فكان أن انتقل إلى شيء من وضوحها وسكونها إلي.
I've noticed more and more people taking conscious measures these days
لاحظت أن المزيد من الناس يأخذون تدابير واعية هذه الأيام
to try to open up a space inside their lives.
لكي يفتحوا فضاءات في حياتهم.
Some people go to black-hole resorts
يذهب البعض منهم إلى منتجعات " الثقب الأسود"
where they'll spend hundreds of dollars a night
حيث ينفقون مئات الدولارات لليلة الواحدة
in order to hand over their cell phone and their laptop
لكي يضعوا هاتفهم النقال وحاسوبهم
to the front desk on arrival.
لدى مكتب الاستقبال عند وصولهم.
Some people I know, just before they go to sleep,
بعض ممن أعرفهم، قبل أن يخلدوا للنوم،
instead of scrolling through their messages
عوض المرور على رسائلهم
or checking out YouTube,
أو تصفح اليوتيوب،
just turn out the lights and listen to some music,
فإنهم يطفؤون الأضواء ويستمعون للموسيقى،
and notice that they sleep much better
وقد لاحظوا أنهم ينامون بشكل أفضل
and wake up much refreshed.
ويستيقظون بنشاط أكثر.
I was once fortunate enough
كنت مرة محظوظا بما يكفي
to drive into the high, dark mountains behind Los Angeles,
لكي أقود سيارتي عبر تلك الجبال الشاهقة والمظلمة خلف لوس أنجلوس،
where the great poet and singer
حيث كان الشاعر والمغني الكبير
and international heartthrob Leonard Cohen
وحبيب الملايين ليونارد كوهن
was living and working for many years as a full-time monk
يعيش ويعمل طوال سنوات كراهب بدوام كامل
in the Mount Baldy Zen Center.
في مركز ماونت بالدي زين.
And I wasn't entirely surprised
ولم أكن متفاجئا كثيرا
when the record that he released at the age of 77,
حين بلغ ألبومه الذي أطلقه في سن 77،
to which he gave the deliberately unsexy title of "Old Ideas,"
والذي أطلق عليه عمدا العنوان غير المثير "أفكار قديمة"،
went to number one in the charts in 17 nations in the world,
المركز الأول في قوائم 17 دولة في العالم،
hit the top five in nine others.
وكان ضمن أفضل 5 أغان في تسع دول أخرى.
Something in us, I think, is crying out
أعتقد أن هناك شيء ما فينا، يطالب
for the sense of intimacy and depth that we get from people like that.
بنوع من الحميمية والعمق التي نحصل عليها من أناس كهؤلاء.
who take the time and trouble to sit still.
أولئك الذين يستغلون الوقت والمشاكل ليبقوا ساكنين.
And I think many of us have the sensation,
وأعتقد أن العديد منا لديه هذا الإحساس، أنا متأكد
that we're standing about two inches away from a huge screen,
أننا نقف على بعد إنشين من شاشة ضخمة،
and it's noisy and it's crowded
صاخبة ومزدحمة
and it's changing with every second,
ومتغيرة في كل ثانية،
and that screen is our lives.
وتلك الشاشة هي حياتنا.
And it's only by stepping back, and then further back,
لذا فعن طريق الرجوع خطوة إلى الوراء، وأخرى إلى الأمام،
and holding still,
والحفاظ على سكوننا،
that we can begin to see what the canvas means
يمكننا أن نرى ما الذي يعنيه ذلك الستار
and to catch the larger picture.
وأن نلتقط صورة أكبر.
And a few people do that for us by going nowhere.
يقوم العديد من الناس بهذا من أجلنا من خلال البقاء في أماكنهم.
So, in an age of acceleration,
إذا، وفي عصر السرعة،
nothing can be more exhilarating than going slow.
ما من شيء أكثر متعة من التحرك ببطء.
And in an age of distraction,
وفي عصر الذهول،
nothing is so luxurious as paying attention.
ما من شيء أكثر فخامة من الانتباه.
And in an age of constant movement,
وفي عصر الحركة المستمرة،
nothing is so urgent as sitting still.
ما من شيء أكثر استعجالا من السكون.
So you can go on your next vacation
لذا فيمكنك الذهاب في عطلتك المقبلة
to Paris or Hawaii, or New Orleans;
إلى باريس أو هاواي، أو نيو أورلينز؛
I bet you'll have a wonderful time.
أراهن أنك ستقضي وقتا ممتعا.
But, if you want to come back home alive and full of fresh hope,
ولكن، إن أردت العودة إلى الديار مفعما بالحياة وبالأمل،
in love with the world,
وغارقا في حب العالم،
I think you might want to try considering going nowhere.
فإنني أعتقد أنه ربما عليك أن تفكر في البقاء في مكانك.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)